Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/vedangsingh1 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

People Management Generative Al Microsoft Copilot

Languages

Hindi

English

Certifications

Microsoft SQL Server 2016 Certification (70-761)

AZ-900 Azure Exam: Microsoft

Azure Fundamentals

Azure Databricks Academy: Data Engineering

Service Design: Designing for Experience Over Time

Honors-Awards

Business Improvement Award Special Recognition Award FC Austin Scholarship

Publications

Digital supply-chain transformation with a human face

Improving warehouse operations—digitally

Computer-aided Design of Asymmetric Gear

Vedang Singh

Product Leader @ Al Agents for industries | Ex - McKinsey | IIT, Kellogg

Austin, Texas, United States

Summary

Group Product Manager with over 15 years' experience in enterprise software, including people leadership experience. Currently leading the development of language-powered agents in Microsoft Copilot for Industries, focused on shipping products that automate business processes and enhance productivity. Prior to Microsoft, spearheaded the development of a supply chain planning solution at McKinsey and an oil and gas pipeline flow modeling software at Shell.

Experience

Microsoft

Principal Product Manager Lead (Al Agents for Industries) 2020 - Present (4 years)

- Leading the strategy and product management for tooling for ISVs in Microsoft Cloud for Industries to build copilots more efficiently, reducing cost and time-to-market. Ship reusable components for ISVs, including finetuned models, skills, prompt libraries, and test suites, to streamline copilot development.
- Managed product development for Microsoft's low-code no-code Power platform.
- Shipped Microsoft's Vaccination Management platform used by 1500+ customers and 3M+ users in 70+ countries.

McKinsey & Company Engagement Manager (Supply Chain Solutions) 2017 - 2020 (3 years)

Jersey

Planned and shipped software for customers to transform their supply chain performance. Few examples:

- Led product development of SaaS solution to improve supply chain planning
- Identified use cases and built business case and roadmap for "Factory of Future" for IoT technologies and advanced analytics
- Owned development of manufacturing network optimization tool

Shell

Senior Associate Engineer (Fluid Dynamics Software) 2009 - 2015 (6 years)

- Managed development for flow management software to ensure reliable oil and gas delivery accounting for 60% of Brunei's annual GDP; Promoted as youngest team lead in BSP's history
- Built business case and initiated deployment of IoT technologies (e.g., predictive maintenance, remote monitoring) to demonstrate operational safety; Prevented shutdown of pipelines carrying oil worth \$3M daily
- Accelerated design roadmap for a \$500M offshore platform by 3 months as a TPM, working with designers, engineers, and finance

Reliance System Engineer 2008 - 2008 (less than a year)

Tata Motors Design Engineer 2007 - 2007 (less than a year)

Education

Indian Institute of Technology, Guwahati Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech.)

Northwestern University - Kellogg School of Management Master of Business Administration (M.B.A.), Economics